Hello, everyone is welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have another
episode in our series
about small talks.
So small talk Marco is what exactly?
Quick little conversation
that you have
maybe with a colleague
or friend or even with
a stranger, maybe
in the elevator, just
about the weather or
some small little topic.
So you're not talking
about the meaning of
life, you're talking about
the weather or food.
So let's check out today's
dialogue and we'll be
back in a minute to talk
more about what's going on.
Oh, dear miss, you are soaked.
Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
Yes, it sure is.
I had to run here from work.
I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please, why don't
you go ahead of me in line.
I'm in no hurry.
Oh, that's so nice of you.
Thank you very much.
My pleasure, miss.
Actually, could you recommend what
to eat here I've never been here before?
Sure.
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious
and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
Personally, I think the beef
salad is the tastiest choice.
I usually get that.
Also, the milkshakes are
the best milkshakes in town.
Well, thanks for the suggestions.
Yeah, don't mention it.
All right, we're back.
So as we saw in this
dialogue, it's a small
talk conversation with two strangers
who are actually buying some food.
So this is something
that could happen if
you are waiting in
line at a supermarket, if
you're at the bank, or even
at a shop like in this case.
Exactly.
This kind of conversation
happens all the time.
So let's take a look at some words and
phrases in today's language takeaway.
All right, so the first
word that we have for
you today is the
gentleman, the older person,
noticed how wet the girl,
what she said, you are soaked.
All right, so it's raining outside and
he says, oh, dear, miss, you are soaked.
All right, this is an adjective.
It describes what she looks like.
So if you are soaked, it means
that you are a little bit wet.
Very wet.
You know, you can say
that someone is a little
wet, but if they're
soaked, it means they're
shoes, they're pants, they're shirt,
they're hat, everything is very wet.
Okay, you are soaked.
And so it's an adjective, even though it
has an ED ending, it may look like a verb
or in the past, but it's not, it's
an adjective with an ED ending.
That's right.
So it's raining outside, this woman
is very wet, she's soaked, she's wet.
And she says, I have to rush, I
have to hurry because of what?
Because I'm on my lunch
break, she's on her lunch break.
Okay, so during work, we might
have something called a break.
This is a short time when we don't
have to work, five minutes, ten minutes.
And the break that we have
at lunch when we get to eat
is a little bit longer, so
we call this a lunch break.
That's right.
So usually people have
their lunch break, let's
say at noon or one o'clock and
it's usually an hour like you say.
That's right, an hour.
Okay, so she's on her lunch break
and that's why she's in a hurry.
And so the other guy let her go in front of
him and he asked her for some suggestions.
What is good here?
What do you recommend to eat?
That's right.
So he's not familiar with
the food, but the woman is
and she says, well, the
avocado sandwich is delicious.
Now let's talk about this fruit
because it is a fruit, right Marco?
It's a fruit and avocado, you see this, it
looks like a big green pear, more or less.
So it's green on the
inside and it's dark on
the outside, so to eat it
you have to take off the skin.
Yeah, that's right.
And inside it's kind
of a buttery almost,
you kind of, it's not
hard like like a banana
or an apple, it's kind of more very, very
soft, you can take it out with the spoon.
That's right.
It's very, very delicious
and it's very common
in a lot of Latin
cooking where you have,
for example, guacamole in Mexican cooking,
which is made primarily of avocados.
That's right.
So she recommends the
avocado sandwich and
then she goes on to
describe some of the food
and now here we're going to take a look at
some adjectives, but in a superlative form.
For example, she said it's the healthiest
thing on the menu, this sandwich.
Okay, so this is a really important point,
Marco, and I'm glad you brought it up.
I can say that this food is healthy,
that means it's good for my body.
But if I say that it's the
healthiest, what does that mean?
How is that different from healthy?
Basically, you're
saying that it's the on
the list of things that are at the
restaurant maybe that are healthy.
This is the most healthy, but you don't
say most healthy, you say healthiest.
Healthy yes.
Okay, so is chocolate cake the
healthiest thing on the menu?
No, probably not.
It's probably the least healthy.
So on top we have the healthiest thing on
the menu, we also have another superlative.
We heard the word tastiest.
Right.
The adjective "tasty" is delicious, it's
tastier, taste good, but here we're saying
that it's the thing that tastes
the best, the tastiest choice.
Okay, so I think that the
avocado sandwich is the tastiest.
That means I think it's
the best thing you can eat.
And that's another one actually.
Best is another
superlative, but it's a
little bit different because
it's not an "s", "east".
Right.
Like tastiest or
healthiest, it's just best.
You're saying that it's
the number one, so the
best milkshake in town,
like in this dialogue
or you say the best soccer
player in the world is so and so.
All right, so this comes
from the adjective "good".
So we have "good", which is not bad, and
the best, which is the most good, right?
Yeah, exactly.
But you don't say the
most good, you say the best.
He's the best.
Maybe Ronaldo is the one of
the best soccer players in the world.
Exactly.
All right, so now let's take
a break, let's take a look at
everything again and we'll be
right back with Fluency Builder.
Oh, dear Miss, you are soaked.
Wow, it's really raining heavily outside.
Yes, it sure is.
I had to run here from work.
I need to rush as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please, why don't
you go ahead of me in line?
I'm in no hurry.
Oh, that's so nice of
you, thank you very much.
My pleasure, Miss,
actually, could you
recommend what to eat here
I've never been here before?
Sure.
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious
and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
Personally, I think the beef salad is
the tastiest choice, I usually get that.
Also, the milkshakes are
the best milkshakes in town.
Well, thanks for the suggestions.
Yeah, don't mention it.
All right, we're back,
so now let's take a
look at three phrases we
picked out on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So we have a great phrase
here, something that we
often hear in conversation,
polite conversations.
The older man
says, "I'm in no hurry.
" Mm-hmm.
Now, what does this mean?
Does this mean he needs to go somewhere?
No, he says, you know what, I
really don't have to go anywhere fast.
That's why he let her, the girl, get
in front of him in line at the shop.
All right, so basically
it means I can wait.
I can wait, yeah.
So if somebody says,
"Oh, I'll be right back,
please wait a moment," you can
say, "I'm in no hurry, take your time.
" Okay, so I'm in no hurry
means it's not that important.
I don't have to go fast.
Right, but if you change
the "no," and you say, "I'm
in a hurry," then that means
that you have to go fast.
Come on, Marco, speed it up.
I'm in a hurry, in a hurry, okay?
Exactly.
So just changing those two words that
gives you a completely different meaning.
And well, the girl Michelle, she
said, "Oh, that's so nice of you.
Thank you very much.
" And he says, "My pleasure."
All right, so this is an alternative
to the phrase, "You're welcome.
" Mm-hmm.
Okay, this is a very polite
way to say, "You're welcome.
" And so when we hear
her thinking for something,
you know, thank you for
letting me go ahead of you.
Mm-hmm.
This is a great, great phrase for you guys.
Exactly.
So now you have
another alternative instead
of saying, "You're
welcome," or, "No problem,"
or, "Don't mention it," now
you have, "It's my pleasure.
" This is a little bit more formal, but
you can use it in any circumstance.
That's right.
And as I said, another
option here is the
phrase, "Don't mention it," which
means exactly the same thing.
You're welcome.
That's right.
So the older gentleman says, "Thanks
for the suggestions, thanks for your help.
" And what does the
young woman say?
"Don't mention it.
" "Don't mention it.
" So this is more colloquial.
This is a little bit more spoken language.
Mm-hmm.
She's saying, "No problem.
You're welcome."
That's right.
So you have, "You're welcome, no problem.
My pleasure.
Don't mention it.
" All ways of saying
the same thing.
All right.
So let's take another
listen to our dialogue.
We'll be back in a moment.
Dear Miss, you are soaked.
Wow.
It's really raining heavily outside.
Yes.
It sure is.
I had to run here from work.
I need to rush, as I'm on my lunch break.
Well, please.
Why don't you go ahead of me in line?
I mean, no hurry.
Oh, that's so nice of you.
Thank you very much.
My pleasure, Miss.
Actually, could you recommend what
to eat here I've never been here before?
Sure.
Well, the avocado sandwich is delicious,
and it's the healthiest thing on the menu.
Personally, I think the beef
salad is the tastiest choice.
I usually get that.
Also, the milkshakes are
the best milkshakes in town.
Well, thanks for the suggestions.
Yeah, don't mention it.
All right.
We're back.
So talking about these
superlatives, I know it's
a complicated subject,
because grammar-wise,
it can be a little bit
difficult to determine
when do you say, for
example, beautiful?
Do you say, "more beautiful,"
or do you say, "beautiful" list?
You say, "more
beautiful," well, I don't
really have a hard and
fast rule for everyone.
It's one of those things
that you learn while
you're studying English and
you just have to remember.
Yes, there are some
exceptions, but usually
you can guide yourself by adjectives
that have usually three or more syllables.
You probably have to use most or more.
Amazing.
Right.
You don't say, "amazingist.
" Most amazing.
Most amazing or more amazing.
You're about funny.
Funny.
So then you say, "funnier,"
or "funniest," or "sad.
" You can say, "sadist.
" All right.
So sad, funny.
These are one and two syllables,
sad, funny, saddest, funniest.
You can use this ending.
But with the words like, "beautiful,"
or "amazing," there are three syllables.
They're long.
You have to say, "most.
" Amazing.
Most beautiful.
Yeah.
And there are some exceptions to the rule.
You may find them.
Usually, if you see
an adjective that's a
little bit long like
this, you can just say,
you can just use more for the
comparative or most for the superlative.
All right.
So lots of stuff there.
I recommend that you
guys go check out the
dialogue and expansion
sentences we have for today.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.